dusbus.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy - DusBus

What is this Privacy Policy for?

This privacy policy is for this website **www.dusbus.com**  and served by **DUSBUS**  and governs the privacy of its users who choose to use it.

The policy sets out the different areas where user privacy is concerned and outlines the obligations & requirements of the users, the website and website owners. Furthermore the way this website processes, stores and protects user data and information will also be detailed within this policy.

**COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION**

Liking, Commenting and Sharing – You may use your account on social network services (such as Facebook, Twitter and Google) for liking, commenting, sharing in or through our services. Please note that social network services are operated by third parties and are not controlled by us. We encourage you to check the applicable privacy policy on each social network and adjust your privacy settings accordingly . Creating and posting content – some features of our Services allow users to create and post content in or through the Services. Any content which you have publicly posted or published on or through our Services shall be publicly available by default, and your profile information may appear in the Services as the creator thereof.

**Creating a DusBus  Account: **

Some part of the Services may require you to create a DusBus account by voluntarily providing your information such as your name and email address either using the WordPress CMS on which the site is run or by logging in to your account in another service (such as Facebook, Twitter and Google). You may further voluntarily provide us with additional information such as your birthday date, gender, location, profile picture and friend list. Such personal information will only be used to operate, maintain, enhance and provide you with our Services.

Protection of your Account – You may never use another’s account without permission. You are solely responsible for the activity that occurs on your account, and you must keep your account password secure. You must notify us immediately of any breach of security or unauthorized use of your account. We will not be liable for your losses caused by any unauthorized use of your account. Profile and Other Information – If you have a DusBus account, your profile information (such as nickname, gender and location), information or content you submit, post, like or comment on, and your other activities on the services will be publicly visible. When you register or post information or content on or through the Services, we suggest you to think carefully about what you are making public.

Contact Information – We may use your contact information such as email address, without further notice, to send you information about our Services, respond to your requests, or facilitate your use of the Services.

Cookies – Like many reputed websites, we may use cookies and beacons to assist in delivering the Services and to collect usage data for improvement of our Services. Cookies are identifiers in the form of text files that are inserted and stored by your web browser on your hard drive. Persistent and session cookies are used to identify unique visitors and to provide a customized user experience. Log Data – Like many other websites and mobile applications, we receive log data when you interact with our Services for delivering our Services and track, customize and improve them. Log data may include information such as internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, kind and version of operating system, date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, link click behavior etc. Third-Party Services – We are not responsible for practices employed by any websites or mobile applications linked to or from our Services. Please be aware that this Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third-party services. Hence we encourage you to read applicable privacy policy on each website or mobile application that you visit. Service Providers – We may use various third-party services to provide our Services and to understand the use of our Services. These third parties may have access to your information to the extent it is reasonably necessary.

### The Website

This website and its owners take a proactive approach to user privacy and ensure the necessary steps are taken to protect the privacy of its users throughout their visiting experience. This website complies to all Indian national laws and requirements for user privacy.

#### Use of Cookies

This website may uses cookies to better the users experience while visiting the website. Where applicable this website uses a cookie control system allowing the user on their first visit to the website to allow or disallow the use of cookies on their computer / device. This complies with recent legislation requirements for websites to obtain explicit consent from users before leaving behind or reading files such as cookies on a user’s computer / device.

Cookies are small files saved to the user’s computers hard drive that track, save and store information about the user’s interactions and usage of the website. This allows the website, through its server to provide the users with a tailored experience within this website.  
Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and its external serving vendors.

This website uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. This software is provided by Google Analytics which uses cookies to track visitor usage. The software will save a cookie to your computers hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website, but will not store, save or collect personal information. You can read Google’s privacy policy here for further information [[http://www.google.com/privacy.html ](http://www.google.com/privacy.html)].

Other cookies may be stored to your computers hard drive by external vendors when this website uses referral programs, sponsored links or adverts. Such cookies are used for conversion and referral tracking and typically expire after 30 days, though some may take longer. No personal information is stored, saved or collected.

## Contact & Communication

Users contacting this website and/or its owners do so at their own discretion and provide any such personal details requested at their own risk. Your personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use. Every effort has been made to ensure a safe and secure form to email submission process but advise users using such form to email processes that they do so at their own risk.

This website and its owners use any information submitted to provide you with further information about the products / services they offer or to assist you in answering any questions or queries you may have submitted. This includes using your details to subscribe you to any email newsletter program the website operates but only if this was made clear to you and your express permission was granted when submitting any form to email process. Or whereby you the consumer have previously purchased from or enquired about purchasing from the company a product or service that the email newsletter relates to. This is by no means an entire list of your user rights in regard to receiving email marketing material. Your details are not passed on to any third parties.

## Email Newsletter

This website operates an email newsletter program, used to inform subscribers about products and services supplied by this website. Users can subscribe through an online automated process should they wish to do so but do so at their own discretion. Some subscriptions may be manually processed through prior written agreement with the user.

Email marketing campaigns published by this website or its owners may contain tracking facilities within the actual email. Subscriber activity is tracked and stored in a database for future analysis and evaluation. Such tracked activity may include; the opening of emails, forwarding of emails, the clicking of links within the email content, times, dates and frequency of activity [this is by no far a comprehensive list].  
This information is used to refine future email campaigns and supply the user with more relevant content based around their activity.

We have tied up with a reputed 3rd party vendor, MailChimp for our e-mail subscription services.  You may also check their privacy policy by clicking on the relevant link given below.

## External Links

Although this website only looks to include quality, safe and relevant external links, users are advised adopt a policy of caution before clicking any external web links mentioned throughout this website. (External links are clickable text / banner / image links to other websites.

The owners of this website cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite their best efforts. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.

## Adverts and Sponsored Links

This website may contain sponsored links and adverts. These will typically be served through our advertising partners, to whom may have detailed privacy policies relating directly to the adverts they serve.

Clicking on any such adverts will send you to the advertisers website through a referral program which may use cookies and will track the number of referrals sent from this website. This may include the use of cookies which may in turn be saved on your computers hard drive. Users should therefore note they click on sponsored external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.

## Social Media Platforms

Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that this website and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.

Users are advised to use social media platforms wisely and communicate / engage upon them with due care and caution in regard to their own privacy and personal details. This website nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms and encourage users wishing to discuss sensitive details to contact them through primary communication channels such as by telephone or email.

This website may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question. Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.

## Shortened Links in Social Media

This website and its owners through their social media platform accounts may share web links to relevant web pages. By default some social media platforms shorten lengthy urls .

Users are advised to take caution and good judgement before clicking any shortened urls published on social media platforms by this website and its owners. Despite the best efforts to ensure only genuine urls are published many social media platforms are prone to spam and hacking and therefore this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any shortened links.

## Resources & Further Information
